Guide to the Gabriel A. Almond Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Additional Papers, 1939-2001; Accession ARCH-2002-254
  - Lecture notes: political economy of third world (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Lecture notes: political economy of development (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Lecture notes: transitions to democracy, 1984-1985 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Lecture notes: Luiz on theories of democratic breakdown (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Lecture notes: Lindblom on politics and markets (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Lecture notes: transfer of progress (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Lecture notes: third world development strategies (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Lecture notes: National War College, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Lecture notes: convocation talk (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Lecture notes: author's talk on Progress and Its Discontents, 1983 Dec 7 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Lecture notes: public policy (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Lecture notes: on the 1986 elections (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Lecture notes: modernization diagrams, 1975 Apr 21 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Lecture notes: Atlantic Alliance (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Lecture notes: Berkeley Colloquium on Development (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Lecture notes: political performance (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Lecture notes: politics and human biology (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Lecture notes: making of American foreign policy (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Lecture notes: 3 issues in contemporary political science (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Lecture notes: processes of American foreign policy making (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Lecture notes: idea of Europe, 1974 May 18 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Lecture notes: pluralism (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Lecture notes: trends in recent social history (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Lecture notes: science, technology and progress (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Lecture notes: talk on receiving Newitt Sanford Award (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Lecture notes: the Bible (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Lecture notes: miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
  - Lecture at Northern Illinois University, "Separate Tables: Schools and Sects in Political Science," Nov. 1987 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Working materials, correspondence - fundamentalism project [unprocessed], 1987-1997 (Box 14)
  - Unalphabetized correspondence[unprocessed], 1998-2002 (Box 14)
  - "Almond Casual" [unprocessed] (Box 15)
  - Articles A-H [unprocessed] (Box 15)
  - Articles I-Z [unprocessed] (Box 16)
- Additional Papers, 1946-1985; Accession ARCH-2003-017
  - Eckstein, Harry - Case Study and Theory in Macropolitics, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lipset, Seymour Martin - Typescript article (1982) and two published articles (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Royalties - Little, Brown, and Co., 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Verba, Sidney and Almond-Political Capability and Political Development, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - SSRC, Committee on Political Behavior - report on activities, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Almond - Communism and Political Culture Theory, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lasswell, Harold Dwight - biographical articles (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Almond - Progress and its Discontents, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Almond - Political Science, the APSA, and Madisonian Political Theory, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Almond - Public Opinion and National Security Policy, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Social Science Research Council [1969 memorandum, 1982 newsletter] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Almond and Scott C. Flanagan - Brian Barry on Crisis, Choice, and Change, circa 1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Almond - Corporatism, Pluralism, and Professional Memory, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Almond - Evaluating Political Goods and Productivity, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Almond and Scott C. Flanagan, Brian Barry (Rebuttal of his critique) -- includes correspondence, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Almond - International Politics and National Politics, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Reviews - Politics of the Developing Areas (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Almond - Introduction to Propensities and Opportunities, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Almond - Political Attitudes of German Business, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Almond - Politics, Science, and Ethics, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Almond - Anthropology, Political Behavior, and International Relations, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Almond - Determinacy-Choice, Stability-Change: Some Thoughts on a Contemporary Polemic in Political Theory, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Almond - Rake's or Pilgrim's Progress, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Almond - Political Development: Analytical and Normative Perspectives, ca. 1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Almond - Politische systeme und politischer Wandel, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Almond - Political Theory and Political Science, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Almond - Slaying the Functional Dragon: A Reply to Stanley Rothman [post 1973] (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Almond - Remarks from Background, Journal of the International Studies Association, 1965 Nov (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Almond - Introduction [to book on public higher education in California] (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Almond - Strategie per lo studio dello sviluppo politico, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Almond- Some reflections on the crisis of the university curriculum reprinted from Daedalus, Journal of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Almond - Toward a Comparative Politics of Eastern Europe, reprint, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Faces of Change Task Force Report: Political Science, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Almond and Stephen J. Genco - Nuvole, orologi e lo studio della politica, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Almond - La cultura politica: storia intellettuale del concetto, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Almond - Interview in News for Teachers of Political Science, 1981 winter (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Almond - How Many Anti-Nazi Germans? The New Republic, 1946 Feb. 4 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 23-24)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
  - Trip to England (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Almond - A Developmental Approach to Political Systems, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Almond - Comparative Political Systems, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Reviews: Politics of the Developing Areas (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence and other materials re book The Politics of the Developing Areas, 1958-1960 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Charles Tilly, correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Lucian Pye, correspondence, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - G. Bingham Powell, correspondence, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Richard Rose, correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Paul Sniderman, correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Sheldon S. Wolin, correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Nie (Norman), Prewitt (Kenneth), Powell (G. Bingham), correspondence re article, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - James S. Coleman, correspondence, 1964-1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Alexander L. George, correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - James W. White, correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Pablo Gonzalez Casanova, correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Lewis J. Edinger, correspondence, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - A. O. Hirschman, correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Wayne A. Cornelius, Jr., correspondence, 1968-1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Council Meeting of the American Political Science Association [bound volume of documents], 1965 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Council Meeting of the American Political Science Association [bound volume of documents], 1966 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Scott Flanagan, 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Thomas Headrick, 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Rajni Kothari, 1965-1972 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Norman Nie Dissertation (correspondence), 1970 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Almond - Developmental Models for the New Nations (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Almond - A. I. D. Talk, 1967 May (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Almond - Economic Growth and Democracy, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Almond – "Perspectives on Political Development" for Benedict Lectures at Boston College, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Almond - Notes on Political Development Theory, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Comments on Almond's book Appeals of Communism, 1950s (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - A German Schoolteacher Writes About the Other Germany, reprint, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - The Politics of the Developing Areas, reviews of (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - A Comparative Study of Interest Groups and the Political Process, reprint, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - The Resistance and the Political Parties of Western Europe, reprint, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Public Opinion and National Security Party, reprint, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Political Ideas of Christian Democracy, reprint, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Public Opinion and the Development of Space Technology, reprint, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Almond - Political Systems and Political Change, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Almond - Democracy and the New Nations, Stanford Today, 1964 autumn (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - A Developmental Approach to Political Science, reprint, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Political Attitudes of Wealth, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Almond - Remarks, International Studies Association, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Almond - Democracy and Foreign Policy Making: Some Comparative Observations on the U. S. and Japan, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - SSRC, Committee on Comparative Politics, A Report on the Activities of the Committee, 1954-1970, 1971 Mar (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Conference on Patterns of U.S. Occupation Policies (held at Stanford University, May 1986) - Almond’s paper "Some Introductory Reflections on Occupations" (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - H. D. Lasswell biographical memoir by Almond - correspondence and text, 1984-1986 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - A. L. George, "Case Studies and Theory Development," – reading for Almond's class, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Nie, Prewitt, Powell (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Newitt Sanford Award (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Herring - 80th Birthday (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Australia, 1983 Sept (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Retirement, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Lasswell Memorabilia (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Fagan (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Chinese Academy of Social Sciences (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Almond - Problem of Hoover Governance and Ward Report, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Madison Award, citation and address by Almond, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Almond (Personal) (Box 8, Folder 11-12)
  - Almond - Personal Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - National Academy of Sciences (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Lasswell, H. D. - biographical memoir by Almond (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Volker Rittberger, 1970-1972 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Robert Springborg, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Royalties, 1970-80 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Royalties, 1980-84 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Comparative Politics Today - Contracts and Royalty Arrangements (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Little, Brown, and Co. - Contracts and General Financial, 1969-1984 (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
  - Comparative Politics Today, correspondence re re-issue, 1976-1983 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Comparative Politics Today II Materials, 1978-1980 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Little, Brown, and Co. Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Crisis, Choice, and Change, correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Princeton University Press correspondence, 1967-1979 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Crisis, Choice, and Change reviews (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
  - Civic culture revisited – correspondence, 1975 Jan 1- (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
  - Civic culture revisited – correspondence, 1975 Jan 1- (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - China Trip, 1981-1983 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Brazil Trip, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - China Trip, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - China Trip, lecture notes and outlines (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - The Three Revolutions of Our Time, 1969 Jul (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - State Building in Britain, France, and Prussia, 1970 Jul (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - The American People and Foreign Policy (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - Almond - TSS, assorted titles (Box 12, Folder 3-5)
  - Social Science Research Council (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Introduction: Public Opinion and Public Policy (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Chapter 2: The Psychological Impact of the Cold War (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Chapter 3: American Character and Foreign Policy (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Research graph - women and foreign policy (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Research graph - occupational groups and foreign policy (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Research graph - income groups (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Research graph - education and foreign policy (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Research graph - youth and foreign policy (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Research graph - regional breakdown and foreign policy (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Research graphs assorted (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Chapter 4: General Orientation toward Foreign Policy (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Chapter 5: Changes in the Foreign Policy Mood (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Chapter 6: Social Groups and the Foreign Policy Mood (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Chapter 7: The Elites and Foreign Policy (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Chapter 8: The Foreign Policy Consensus (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Chapter 9: Competing Foreign Policies (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Chapter 9: Problems and Perspectives (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Stray pages from foreign policy manuscript (Box 13, Folder 18)